NAA Records 5775
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Membership Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  List of the committee members (1967); Request for application materials, and the cover letter sent with such materials (1968); Letter from member requesting an additional copy of the membership directory (1968); Letter requesting checks to cover the committee's expenses (1968); Letter from the committee chairman to the secretary stating that he had notified certain applicants that they are likely to be accepted into membership, also requests that the secretary send these applicants the registration and reservation forms (1967); Biographical resumes of applicants and blank comment sheets (1967); Cover letter to application materials sent to Allan Walt (1967); Correspondence in regards to the death of member Marion Beatty (1967); Letter requesting the sending of application materials and cover letter sent with such materials (1967); Correspondence regarding member Albert J. Hoban, includes: a letter sent to him at the NLRB notifying him of his failure to pay dues, a letter back from the NLRB stating that he is sick, and a letter that accompanied the previous year's dues which noted that because of his new position he would not be doing arbitration, but that he wished to remain "on the rolls" (1967); Letter transferring Certificates of Membership for new members to the president for signing (1967); Excerpt from the Board of Governors' meeting minutes, includes: a dues waiver for member Harry Abrahams, a list of the new members, a list of applications being held for further investigation, a list of resignations from the Academy, and notification that 61 Charter Member Certificates have been prepared and issued (1967); Letter from a member requesting that application materials be sent to George E. Bardwell, includes the cover letter sent with such materials (1967); Letters sent to members who have neglected to pay their dues (1967); Letter to member Harry Abrahams notifying him that his dues have been waived (1967); Letter from new member William P. Halloran thanking for his admittance, and noting his enclosed affirmation and dues statement. Also, inquires as to the difference in dues levels. The included Academy reply states that the levels are an indication of the amount of arbitration a member does (1967); Letter from new member thanking for his admittance, and noting enclosed dues statement and check (1967); Letter to member Harry Abrahams notifying him that the Board of Governors voted to waive his dues (1967); Letters making arrangements for new members, includes: sending them the current Volume of Proceedings, inscription of Certificates of Membership, and sending them the insurance material (1967); Letters to new members informing them of their acceptance into membership (1967); List of the names and addresses of the new members (1967); Handwritten letter from the chairman of the committee to the secretary informing the secretary of the new members addresses for the mailing of the acceptance letters (1967); "Report of Membership Committee Board of Governors Meeting October 21. 1967", includes: a list of the applicant's names with their biographical resumes who the committee recommends for admittance, "approved" handwritten with the date by each name, a list of the applicants being held for further processing and brief reasons as to why (1967); Request for application materials, and cover letter sent with such materials (1967); Letter to member explaining why an applicant, whom this member wrote disapprovingly of, was accepted (1967); Dues statement of member Edward J. Allan on which he requests to be put on the list of retired members (1967); Letter from the president to the secretary concerning: the dates of the 1970 meeting, putting on the agenda consideration of Harry Abrahams request for a dues waiver, and questions as to who should make his (the president's) hotel reservations. Letter also states that the president will update the secretary about the speaker for the upcoming annual meeting (1967); Requests for application materials and cover letters sent with such materials (1967); Biographical resumes of applicants with blank comment sheets (1967); Letters requesting application materials and cover letters sent with such materials (1967); Resignation letter from Orme W. Phelps, Academy reply states its regret (1967); Correspondence regarding Samuel Krimsky's application, includes: request for materials, sending in of application, and transferal to committee (1967); Correspondence concerning John R. Coleman, a former Academy member, includes: a letter from Haverford College, where Coleman is about to become president, inquiring if he is still an Academy member, and the Academy reply which states that he resigned and gives his dates of membership (1967); Letter requesting checks to cover committee expenses (1967); Letter transferring a page of the Board of Governors meeting minutes (1967); Cover letter to application materials sent to applicant Ray Marshall (1967); Letter from member E. L. Keller requesting an additional dues statement since he misplaced the first one (1967); Packet of material sent to the membership regarding the possibility of the Academy establishing a pension and retirement program plan (1967); "National Academy of Arbitrators Appointments 1967", a list of officers, board of governors, committee members, editors, and regional chairmen (1967); Letter from applicant J.F.W. Weatherill stating that he is sending his application to the committee chairman (1967); Letter to printer requesting several blank Certificates of Membership for examination by the Academy to determine what the special certificates for charter members should look like (1967); Letter from the secretary to the president noting that the Seibel report (on a pension and retirement plan) will be reproduced and distributed to the membership, and informing that about 60 charter certificates of membership will be made up and will need to be signed by the president and the secretary, and also noting that reimbursements will now be issued for travel expenses of Board of Governors meetings (1967); Letter from a member requesting that application materials be sent to Harry W. Arthurs and I.F.W. Weatherill, included are the cover letters sent with these materials (1967); Cover letter sent with the address plates to get them changed and get new ones made (1967); The committees report from the Board of Governors' Meeting minutes, includes: a list of the new members with notification that one applicant was denied due to insufficient experience, and that the committee is giving further consideration to the application of Walter G. Seinsheimer (1967); "Special Report - Pension Plan Inquiry", from the Board of Governors' meeting minutes, briefly describes some of Larry Seibel's findings and asks him to "consider the discussions and report further on the matter" (1967); Letter from applicant Raymond L. Britton requesting application materials, and the cover letter sent with such materials (1967); Letter from member Jacob Finkelman requesting that his mailing and office addresses appear separately in the directory, Academy reply states that it will be done (1967); Letter from the First National Bank of Denver noting the death of member J. Glenn Donaldson and requesting he be taken off the membership list (1967); Letter to applicant L. Whiting Farinholt, Jr. suggesting that he withdraw his application since it is unlikely he will be accepted due to his insufficient experience, letter also suggests that he reapply at a later date (1967); Letter from the secretary to the president transferring the new members' Certificates of Membership for signing by the president (1967); Letter noting that a committee report could be held until the fall (1967); Letter transferring several applicants' files with an attached that list of the applicants who are recommended for admittance along with their biographical resumes. Letter also outlines the case of Raymond Scheib whom the Academy recommends for rejection on the basis of insufficient experience (1967); Material summarizing dues payments, both how many, and who have paid at each level (1967); Note from member Charles G. Hampton transferring his dues payment, and explaining that it was late due to illness, included is a letter from the Academy thanking him for his payment (1967); Correspondence regarding the resignation of member John R. Coleman resulting from his mail not being forwarded to his new address (1967); Report of the Committee on the Training of New Arbitrators (1967); Material summarizing dues payments, both how many, and who nave paid at each level (1967); Letter responding to member Paul A. Dodd's request for a list of charter members. Letter states that there is no list but the Academy should try to identify who the charter members are, and make one up (1967); Letter from member requesting that application materials be sent to Edward C. King, includes the cover letter sent with such materials (1967); Academy reply to an invitation to SUNY Buffalo's new president's inauguration ceremony which states that member David R. Kochery will be present to represent the Academy (1967); Letter noting that the committee will not have a report for the May 6 Board of Governors' meeting (1967); Letter from member enclosing dues payment, and the Academy reply thanking for payment (1967); Correspondence regarding John R. Coleman's resignation which resulted from what he felt was a rude letter concerning his failure to pay dues (he did not receive the earlier letters due to a change in his address, only the final notice). The Academy's reply explains the procedure and apologizes for any offense (1967); Letters staffing the committee (1967); Letter of resignation, due to bad health, from member Thomas Norton (1967); Letters making arrangements for new members, includes: inscription of Certificates of Membership, and the sending of insurance materials (1967); Letter sent to new members informing them of their acceptance into membership (1967); Letter listing the names and addresses of the new members (1967); Material concerning the death of member J. Glenn Donaldson, including: a letter notifying the president, an obituary, and a sympathy letter sent to his wife (1967); Form sent out to membership to get their preferences as to the month they would like the annual meeting to be held in (1967); Letters sent to members who have failed to pay their dues informing them that if their dues are not received, they will be suspended (1967); Letter from committee chairman to the president informing him who the committee's members will be for the year (1967)
- Membership Committee, 1953-1970 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  Packet of material sent to committee members establishing agenda of the meeting with relevant background material, includes: a list of applications which are still being processed along with the biographical information ("in" is handwritten by each name), detailed outlines of the events in the Walter G. Seinsheimer, Vernon L. Souffer, and John H. Dorsey cases, a copy of the memo sent out regarding the Seinsheimer case, and a memo noting the time and date of the upcoming committee meeting. Also included are two suggestions about the the application procedure. The first suggests that appropriate applicants be referred to as "proposed" for membership rather than "applying", and the second suggests that sample opinions from each applicant be sent out to the membership along with the biographical resumes (1967); Biographical resumes of applicants, blank comment sheets, and the "Statement of Policy Relative To Membership" (1967); Handwritten notes dated 1/7/67, look like voting figures on applicants (1967); Handwritten letter thanking for the letter concerning the Kreimer matter (1966); Letter to the committee chairman from committee member Clare B. McDermott thoroughly clarifying the arbitration experience of applicant Hillard Kreimer (1966); Letter inquiring about the committee's circularization practices of information about applicants as applied to the Sinsheimer case (1966); Handwritten notes dated 11/11/66, unclear what they are about (1966); Letter to committee members stating that the September 17 meeting was productive, that a decision was being held on the Stouffer case pending further consideration, and that the next meeting would be on January 7 (1966); Handwritten minutes of the committee's meeting on 9/17/66, lists applicants and their status, notes date, time, and location of next meeting, the rest is unclear (1966); Packet of information for the committee meeting on September 17 and 18, 1966. Includes: the agenda, a list of applicants names, information about them, and some history of their applications, a list of applicants whose applications are still being processed, a list of applicants who are ready to be voted upon, and a list of questions to be raised with the committee (1966); Letter announcing the committee's meeting on September 17 and 18, 1966 (1966); Packet of information which includes: handwritten notes about applicants, including some personal information like age, occupation, or place of work and also "approved", "not approved", or "deferred" written by some names. Also included are the biographical resumes of the applicants, blank comment forms, and two memos to the Board of Governors which list the applicants by the status of their application (for example, "unanimously recommends for admission") (1965-1966); Cover letters sent to applicants with their application materials (1967); Letter sent to Harry Abrahams concerning the Board of Governors' decision to waive his dues in response to his request (1967); Letter to new member in response to his inquiry stating that the levels of dues payment are not defined to designate anything but are understood to "bear some relationship to the amount of arbitration in which the member is engaged" (1967); Correspondence regarding the questioning of the membership policy particularly in regard to members who embarrass the Academy by representational activities or extravagant fees (1967); Letters regarding the date of the summer committee meeting (1967);Letter to the secretary from the committee chairman relating that the committee will not have a report for the May 6 Board of Governors' meeting and that the committee chairman will, thus, not attend (1967); Letters staffing the committee (1967); Letters sent out to members who have failed to pay their dues (1967); Biographical resumes of applicants and blank comment forms (1967); Letters regarding the membership directory, most serving as cover letters to directories sent out, but one regarding an incorrect address for member Jim Hill (1967); Cover letters sent with application materials to applicants (1967); Cover letter sent out with a directory to a person who requested information about the membership policy (1967); Handwritten note, difficult to read and refers to people by their initials. For example, "C. Duff" opposes the application of " I(?). K." and so does "T. McD." (1967); Letter to the committee chairman from the W. New York Regional Chairman, the chairman states that he does not know anything about the two Canadian applicants, but he offers the name of a region member from Canada who might (1969); Letter from a member to an applicant (seemingly the member proposed the applicant for membership) in which the member apologizes for not being aware of the membership case requirement which barred the applicant from admittance, but urges the applicant to reapply when his case figures meet the requirement (1969); Letters to two applicants suggesting that they delay applying until they better meet the Academy's "substantial and current experience" requirement (1969); Reply to a letter from Judge C.E. Hunter which informs him that the Academy "does not conduct or in any other way administer labor arbitrations", also the letter serves as a cover letter for application materials (1970); Cover letters sent with application materials to two applicants (1970); Letters to new members informing them of their acceptance into membership (1970); Letter to applicant Harry F. Stark informing him of the timing of the various decision-making steps on his application (1970); Biographical resumes of applicants with blank comment sheets (1968); Handwritten notes, including: the annual meeting, the pre-annual meeting and post-annual meeting of the Board of Governors' meeting, and a list of the new members (1969); Biographical resumes of the applicants and blank comment forms (1969); Outline of applicants' cases whom the committee recommends for: admittance, rejection, and holding. Two copies (n.d.); Letters sent to new members welcoming them into the Academy (1968); Biographical resumes of applicants and blank comment forms (1967-1969); Letter informing new member Walter L. Eisenberg of his acceptance into the Academy also serving as a cover letter to the usual materials (1968); Letters to two applicants suggesting that they hold applying until their case figures better meet the application requirements (1969); Response to the resignation letter of member Whitley P. McCoy which informs him that his dues have been waived and that he may remain a member of the Academy (1969); Letter regarding the case of applicant Richard Calhoon who was rejected once, but whose application has strong supported by a member, Chuck Douds, who speaks of a substantial number of cases the applicant has done, but, of which the committee can find no evidence (1969); Correspondence regarding the application of Herman Lazarus, an advocate who was requested to withdraw his application, but refused, in objection to the policy (1956); Biographical resumes of applicants, one with either "approved" or "denied" handwritten next to each name (1958?); Supplemental biographical resumes (1953).
- Special Committee on Memorials, 1956-1966 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  routine material
- Committee on New Member Orientation, 1983-1985 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  Certificate of Membership of William A. Babiskin; Packet of the Academy's advisory opinions (1-11); Biographical resumes of applicants with handwritten notes, including: "admitted", "deferred", and "rejected"; Packet of information given to members-elect (new members) prior to the annual meeting, includes: papers from prior NAA proceedings and a set of opinions issued by the committee on Professional Responsibility (1983-1985).
- Nominating Committee, 1962-1976 (Box 38, Folder 16)
- Nominating Committee, 1962-1976 (Box 38, Folder 17)
- Nominating Committee, 1962-1976 (Box 38, Folder 18)
- Nominating Committee, 1948-1984 (Box 39, Folder 1)
- Nominating Committee, 1948-1984 (Box 39, Folder 2)
- Nominating Committee, 1948-1984 (Box 39, Folder 3)
- Nominating Committee, 1948-1984 (Box 39, Folder 4)
- Nominating Committee, 1948-1984 (Box 39, Folder 5)
- Nominating Committee, 1948-1984 (Box 39, Folder 6)
- Nominating Committee, 1948-1984 (Box 39, Folder 7)
- Committee of Overseas Correspondents, 1969-1985 (Box 39, Folder 8)
- Committee on Policy Handbook, 1983-1985 (Box 39, Folder 9)
- Committee on Professional Responsibility and Grievances (Box 39, Folder 10)
- Committee on Professional Responsibility and Grievances (Box 39, Folder 11)
- Committee on Professional Responsibility and Grievances (Box 39, Folder 12)
- Committee on Professional Responsibility and Grievances (Box 39, Folder 13)
- Committee on Professional Responsibility and Grievances (Box 39, Folder 14)
- Committee on Professional Responsibility and Grievances (Box 39, Folder 15)
- Program Committee, 1957-1985 (Box 39, Folder 16)
- Program Committee, 1957-1985 (Box 39, Folder 17)
- Program Committee, 1957-1985 (Box 39, Folder 18)
- Program Committee, 1957-1985 (Box 39, Folder 19)
- Program Committee, 1957-1985 (Box 39, Folder 20)
- Program Committee, 1957-1985 (Box 39, Folder 21)
- Committee on Program Resources, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 22)
- Committee (Tripartite) on Problems of Proof, 1965-1967 (Box 39, Folder 23)
- Publications Committee, 1984 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  Report, October, 2pp.
- Public Employment, Special Committee on Disputes Settlement In:, 1969-1985 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  Reports and routine correspondence
- Railway Adjustment Board Matters, Special Committee On, 1973 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  correspondence setting up the committee
- Re-Examination Committee, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  Proposed language covering the Statement of Policy Relative to Membership; Proposed amendment to Section 7 in Article VI of NAA Bylaws; Report Submitted to the Board of Governors on 12/6, 30pp. (by the Re-Examination Committee, otherwise known as the Special Committee to Review Membership and Related Policy Questions of the Academy); Results of Questionnaire sent to members by the committee; and routine correspondence
- Research, Sub-committee on (Box 40, Folder 5)
  memo, 12pp., reporting on a questionnaire which was sent to members
- Research and Education, Committee on, 1949-1951 (Box 40, Folder 6)
- Research and Education, Committee on, 1953-1956 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  Report, 7pp. and appendices; Report 1/15/54, 7 pp.; Report and Recommendations 1/1/55, 4pp.; and routine correspondence
- Research and Education, Committee on, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  Committee Report 1/1/59, 7pp. not for publication; and routine correspondence
- Research and Education, Committee on, 1960-1961 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  Report, correspondence; Report entitled, "A Statistical Examination of the Ratio of Study Days to Hearing Days Charged by Arbitrators", 11/61, 38pp.
- Research and Education, Committee on, 1962-1965 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  routine correspondence
- Research and Education, Committee on, 1965 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  correspondence re proposed Arbitration Conference
- Research and Education, Committee on, 1975-1976 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  Report of the Committee on "The Steelworker's Trilogy and The Arbitrator", n.d., 4pp.; and routine correspondence
- Research and Education, Committee on, 1977-1980 (Box 40, Folder 13)
- Research and Education, Committee on, 1981-1985 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  Reports, bibliography, routine correspondence
- Seminars, Subcommittee on, 1979-1980 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  Workshop Material Prepared for Discussion Purposes only by the Subcommittee, including: "Discussion Guide on External Law", 1980, 125pp.; "Discussion Guide on Seminars on Federal Sector Grievance Arbitration", 1980, 85pp.; "Transcript of a Session on Remedies", 1979, 34pp.
- Statutory Regulation of Labor Dispute Arbitration, Special Committee on, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  Report, 3pp. and 12pp.
- Steering Committee, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  memo re Draft Code of Professional Responsibility for Arbitrators of Labor-Management Disputes, 4/2, 25pp.
- Structure, Committee on (Box 40, Folder 18)
- Survey Committee, 1962-1965 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  Reports on surveys and statistical compilations
- Training of New Arbitrators, Committee on (Box 40, Folder 20)
  Reports and correspondence
- Committees - general, lists of committee appointments and miscellaneous (Box 40, Folder 21)
- Region 1 - New England, 1977-1982 (Box 41, Folder 1)
- Region 2 - New York City, 1953-1982 (Box 41, Folder 2)
- Region 3 - E. Pennsylvania, 1955-1983 (Box 41, Folder 3)
- Region 4 - District of Columbia, 1952-1983 (Box 41, Folder 4)
- Region 5 Southeast, 1953-1982 (Box 41, Folder 5)
- Region 6 - Upstate New York, 1959-1982 (Box 41, Folder 6)
- Region 7 Canada, 1977-1982 (Box 41, Folder 7)
- Region 8 - W. Pennsylvania, 1977-1982 (Box 41, Folder 8)
- Region 9 Ohio, 1979-1982 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  includes Ohio region NAA Bylaws, n.d. 2pp.; and routine correspondence
- Region 10 Michigan, 1954-1983 (Box 41, Folder 10)
- Region 11 - Illinois (Midwest Region), 1950-1982 (Box 41, Folder 11)